I'm telling you. this-
This is a bad idea.
Well. I heard there's an 80-foot-tall
black walnut tree back here.
- Uh-huh.
- We can get 15 grand for just one tree.
This is government property!
The road said "Closed" in big red letters.
So we get in.
We get the wood. We get out.
- Is that it?
- What are you. a moron?
- This tree's coniferous.
- "Carnivorous?" What?
- It eats meat?
- No. numb-nuts. Needles and cones.
Oh.
Those don't look like cones to me.
Holy Mother of God.
How could you have hired him?
Your father was the best candidate.
Well. are you sure?
Dad is an excellent liar.
He's also an excellent science teacher.
- I called the school where he taught.
- Well. 15 years ago.
And after 15 years.
they still remember him.
They named their lab after your dad.
- I thought you'd be pleased.
- Well. you were incorrect.
- Is there a probation period?
- Yes.
Well. what would please me is if
you terminate him at the end of that time.
Okay. kids. Everybody put on their goggles.
- Hello.
- Hi. honey. Hey.
Okay. Ready. aim. fire.
- The light refracted!
- Yeah. Now why is the light visible?
Because theJell-O molecules
are close together.
Yeah. But that's not magic. That's-
Max K.. the science way.
Science Squad. meet my daughter...
the world-famous anthropologist.
Dr. Temperance Brennan.
Of course. I taught her
everything she knows.
Uh. actually. I went to college.
I have multiple degrees.
Well. tell the kids a little
something about refraction.
Snell's Law states
that the angle of incidence...
is related to the angle of refraction...
where "V'"equals the wave velocities...
through the respective media...
- and "N" equals-
- Nifty. That's very nifty.
But what was your favorite example
when you were a kid?
- Rainbows.
- Rainbows? I love rainbows.
Yeah. rainbows. She used to make me
drive her all the way across town...
to the other side of the rainbow because
she didn't believe...
that light came out of the back
of a raindrop. Yeah.
Yeah. So are there
any questions for our scientist?
- Ooh!
- Me! Me!
Uh. I have to examine the frontal bone
of a dead person's skull.
Maybe another time. kids.
Gee. dead person's skull.
Ain't that a kick in the head?
Most likely a wind deposited them there.
Hmm. That seems most likely?
The bones didn't come from the ground.
and they didn't come from the sky.
- That leaves the wind.
- Those people over there need to clear out.
Those people over there are looking
for the rest of"that. "
They're right in the middle
of the masked booby migration path.
"Masked booby'"? You're kidding.
The Department of Fish
and Wildlife does not kid. Agent Booth.
You just have to give me a minute.
You can have your boobies all to yourself.
- Okay. what do we got?
- This one's a portion of the sacrum.
It's definitely human. There's char marks.
Oh. God. You know. I hate when you sniff
and smell dead things.
Fresh burn-
days or weeks rather than months.
- Found a hyoid!
- Oh. he found a hyoid.
- Dead guy's hyoid.
- "Guy'"as in the sexually nonspecific urban colloquialism...
or in reference to the gender normally
associated with a penis. Mr. Bray?
Um. the penis?
- Similar char marks.
- Any fires in the last couple of weeks?
- No.
- The body of the hyoid is fractured.
- Strangulation.
- This man was murdered.
We'll need to search this entire area.
According to my scientists.
your boobies are out of luck.
Press play. Subtitles appear.
200+ languages. One app:  tryray.app
- Hey. Good afternoon. Agent Booth.
- Max?
Wish I could stay and chat. but I gotta go
pick up my new employment I.D.
- Ooh. Guns of steel.
- You work here now?
Max. you-You work here now?
I can still make out
the accelerant pour pattern.
Victim must've been doused postmortem.
I'll have Hodgins
run it through the mass spec.
- Your dad works here now?
- Not my idea.
- She wants me to fire him.
- Why?
This is a crime lab. My father is
a bank robber and an accused murderer.
Booth's killed more people than Max has.
and he works here.
Don't bring that up.
Why'd you have to bring that up?
In fact. Dr. Brennan.
you've also killed a person.
And. I'll point out.
Max was never convicted.
- So in the eyes of the law. he's never killed anyone.
- Why are you defending him?
- Why aren't you?
- He is your father.
Well. whose sperm hit whose egg
shouldn't determine who works here.
Come on. He's showing kids
around the museum. What can it hurt?
Let's get to work. please.
Nothing definitive on cause of death.
- Of course. we don't have a lot to work with.
- I did find an anomaly.
The victim suffered
a compression fracture...
- sometime between three and six months prior to his death.
- Why is that an anomaly?
Compression fractures are normally
associated with osteoporosis...
but the sacral vertebrae haven't
even undergone final fusing.
Not even 30 years old.
The fracture must've
been the result of trauma.
A motor vehicle accident.
parachute jumping-
- It would've been very painful.
- Twenty-something with a bad back-
- You gotta give me something here
more to go on. Bones.
I would love to give you more.
Booth. but that would involve fantasy-
- Dr. Saroyan.
- which would be futile.
Excellent. I'll check my e-mail.
It's your lucky day. Booth.
We ran the victim's bone marrow.
We got a hit on the Armed Forces
D.N.A. Registry.
Here's your guy. Calvin Warren.
Force Recon- Marine Corps Special Ops.
Toughest of the tough.
The kind that parachute out of airplanes
and get vertebral compression fractures?
You know what? You are a genius. okay?
Did the Marine Corps say
where this guy got to?
They don't know. Warren was
honorably discharged three years ago.
Marines tried to track him down.
see ifhe wanted to re-up.
Even checked his credit cards and bank accounts.
but he's totally off the grid.
Would his back be bad enough to medicate?
- Yes.
- Okay. fine.
I'll just order a search
of the controlled substance database.
And I'll see if I can get an address.
You guys can go back to your bone play.
Man. can you believe how light this thing is?
I'd say six grams.
No way these bones were burned
in an ordinary wood fire.
A wood fire burns at 800 degrees Fahrenheit.
Human flesh needs 1400 to ignite.
- Why do you know that?
- I've got an uncle who's a funeral director.
Crematorium will incinerate a grown man
down to five or six pounds.
These weren't cremated. The bones would be
drier and the flesh would be completely gone.
Meaning that the burn was hotter than a
wood fire and cooler than a crematorium.
- That's a thousand-degree range.
- I may be able to I.D. the accelerants.
I think we need a broader picture
of the burn conditions.
How are you gonna do that?
We could experiment.
Oh- Oh. is that what you're after here?
You'll recall I mostly disapproved of
your experiments with Dr. Addy.
- You didn't disapprove of the results.
- You have me there. Dr. Hodgins.
I can't tell if we're doing
an experiment or not.
Not.
See. I- I don't see what the problem is.
Well. it's a crime lab.
You're a convicted felon.
Your presence taints the evidence.
But I'm not gonna be around any evidence.
Basically. I'm just gonna be
firing lasers through stuff.
Oh. look. There's the doc that told
the jury that I was a sociopath. Hey.
- Please. Sit down. Doc. How are you?
- Likable sociopath.
So Cam wants Hodgins
to design an experiment...
to figure out how hot a fire was?
Yeah. How hot a fire was
that burned a body.
- What body?
- The "bones in the tree'"murder victim-
which is a crime we cannot discuss.
Yeah. but I know exactly how
that experiment should go.
You aren't adequately credentialed
to design an experiment. Dad.
Can I ask what's
really going on between you?
Tempe doesn't want me
working at theJeffersonian.
- Why?
- Well. it's a conflict of interest.
We catch criminals. My dad is a criminal.
- That would be valid-
- Thank you.
if it were your real reason. but it's not.
- Yes. it is.
- No. it's not.
Yeah. Yes. it is.
- No.
- Yeah. Uh-huh.
- No. it's not.
- Mm-hmm.
No. And-And this can't
be resolved between you...
until you confront the real
reason behind your feelings.
What do you say it is?
Well. at the time you abandoned
your daughter 15 years ago...
you were a well-regarded science teacher.
Now here you are. basically
in the same situation.
And subconsciously.
she doesn't want to risk...
feeling that sense of abandonment
and bereavement again.
Boy. that is such a load of crap.
You are far too rational for that.
Exactly.
F.B.I. got a hit off
the controlled substances database.
I just got off the phone with Booth.
Cal Warren had a prescription
for oxycodone...
written by a Dr. Antonia Ezralow.
- Office in Chevy Chase.
- Could she provide an address?
Dr. Ezralow has never heard
of Calvin Warren.
Plus. she's a dermatologist.
Very rarely writes prescriptions
for pain medication.
So he probably stole her prescription pad.
Here's his MySpace page...
and. I have to say. he doesn't
look much like a drug dealer.
What a waste.
Tall. dark. handsome and dead.
- Too bad he's blocking his address.
- Well. let's see.
This is the house across the street.
Now if I were a house number.
I'd be right about here.
I crop it so all we got is the reflection.
Reverse and re-size.
Tweak the contrast. find some edges.
3- 2-9-4.
So he's across the street from 3294.
But what street?
Well. 1880-ish architecture.
square bay front.
- Let's assume the DC area.
- Check out the lamppost.
Yeah. It places us in one of the two
historical districts...
where they still use those...
cast iron. modified
bishop's crook street lamps.
For an artist. you make
a pretty good detective.
I think you just insulted me.
Okay. Now I do a search for 3294
in those two zip codes...
and I come up with-
Mad skills. babe.
The landlord said that Cal Warren
worked crazy hours.
You know. he kept to himself.
Every time the landlord asked him...
you know. what he did for a living.
he always dodged the question.
- Maybe he liked his privacy.
- What? So much that he pays his rent in cash?
I don't know. Bones. Something is weird.
- It's not right.
- There's no letters.
No photographs. Not even a bill.
So did you persuade Cam to fire Max?
What? You think my dad should be
allowed to work at theJeffersonian?
What? You know. she's just. you know.
trying to do you a favor.
- I didn't ask for a favor.
- Sometimes you don't need to ask.
I got a passport.
This guy's been to countries
I haven't even heard of.
What is this?
I don't know. But this is
something we're familiar with.
Foreign currency. Lots of it.
Booth found this in Tall. Dark.
and Handsome's drawer.
Hmm. It's an R.F. proximity card.
- And that would be-
- Basically. it's a super-fancy key card.
You wave the card
in front of the reader...
it logs your info. and the door opens.
Any way to figure out what door it opens?
Well. if the info on the card isn't
too heavily encrypted.
I heard you tried to get Hodgins
interested in doing an experiment.
Let's just say I planted the seed.
Huh.
- What? C.I. A? N.S. A?
- No.
Dupont Circle.
Special Agent Booth. F.B.I.
Ah!
- Welcome to the Woodbury School. Agent Booth.
- Hi. How are you?
- What's with all the security?
- It's precautionary.
Our student body includes children
of diplomats. heads of state. C.E.O.'s.
- Good morning.
- How old is your child?
Parker? Oh. he's seven.
- Has he been evaluated?
- He does just fine.
Well. most applicant families
engage an educational consultant.
- I mean. it's not a requirement. of course. but-
- Mr. Donnegan...
- I think you got this all wrong.
- I know it seems crazy. but given the demand...
we can only accept
the most qualified applicants.
Oh. Parker's a great kid.
The problem is keeping him
that way. isn't it?
Sixty-eight percent of our students
matriculate to Ivy League universities...
and it's not because of our
electron microscope or A.P. classes.
It's because of our honor code.
Any violation results
in immediate dismissal.
Now. why don't I get you
an admissions packet?
A- Actually. I-
I'm here because
of a murder investigation.
- I'm sorry?
- One of your parking lot access cards...
was found in the apartment
of a victim- a Cal Warren?
He's not a parent or an employee.
I would know the name.
- Maybe we could check your computer.
- Of course.
- No one is issued a key card
without security clearance.
- Thanks.
- One of our fathers...
actually implemented the security system.
He's deputy director of the C.I.A.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
There he is- Calvin Warren.
Did he happen to work for the C.I. A?
No. actually. he works for the president.
Of the United States?
Parents Association.
- As a nanny.
- A nanny?
Twenty-eight grand a year.
I didn't pay that much
for four years of college.
Well. if you think it's so ridiculous.
why did you save the application?
I didn't save it. I just didn't have
a chance to throw it out yet.
You don't have to be embarrassed.
It's perfectly normal
to want the best for Parker.
Public school was good enough for me.
It's good enough for my kid.
Of course it is... probably.
Mmm. what's that supposed to mean?
Parker is a bright. engaged little boy.
I'm sure he'll do fine
in a large classroom.
- I did.
- Except-
- Except what?
- Your dad was a science teacher.
- You're a scientist.
- Yes.
- My education was enriched at home.
- That's what I gotta do-
enrich Parker at home.
In what academics are you qualified
to offer enrichment?
Well-
Ethel. can you grab my bag. please?
I am on my way to
the Children First board meeting.
Thank you.
Oh. Wexler has the groomer at 3:00.
Excuse me. Elsbeth King?
- Yes?
- We're with the F.B.I.
Do you know a Mr. Calvin Warren?
He was my nanny. What happened?
That's exactly what we're investigating.
Cal dropped off the face
of the earth on Sunday.
He was an excellent nanny.
Well. how is it that an ex-Special
Ops guy becomes a nanny?
My husband. Richard. handles defense
contracts- Middle East. South America.
There were kidnap threats a couple
years ago. and Richard was concerned.
He offered Cal 2.500 a week.
That's very good pay for a babysitter.
Cal was more like a bodyguard.
Do you suppose that's what got him killed?
- Someone after my children?
- Um-
- Could we speak to your children?
- Of course.
Okay. so what time
on Sunday did you last see Cal?
- Why?
- Because it's pertinent to our investigation.
- What?
- It's Mandarin Chinese.
My father says the Chinese will run
the planet in 10 years.
He figures it'll be useful.
- That's very smart.
- Okay. well. here. today- Okay? I run the world.
Huh?
He just called you a stupid. inbred sack of meat.
Really?
I'm sorry. Do you have
something to say to me?
- He-He apologized.
- Good.
So you want to tell me
what happened on Sunday?
Well. Cal dropped me off at
the algebra tutor around 8:00...
and then took Lexie
to check out a new horse.
In the afternoon.
you had a game against All Saints.
Lacrosse. I got this.
Let's see.
- Oh. And Cal took you to the emergency room?
- No.
He knew one of the moms was a doctor.
so he figured she'd do a better job.
Looks like the work of a plastic surgeon.
No. dermatologist- Dr. Ezralow.
Very competent.
The Royce boy was stitched up
by the same doctor...
who said she didn't know Cal Warren.
Mm-hmm. I'm having
her brought in for questioning.
You think those kids are
better off than Parker?
Yeah. of course they are.
They have every advantage-
a wonderful school. a successful father...
mother committed to charity work.
I spend more time with my house plants
than they do with their kids.
Well. children of privilege
have always been raised by staff.
That's how the upper one percent
stays the upper one percent.
Assuming quality education
and adequate supervision...
parents are actually rather irrelevant
beyond a certain age.
- You're kidding me.
- Look at this.
They start Latin in third grade.
That's fantastic.
No. You know what's more important
than academic enrichment?
A loving environment. You ask anyone.
Parker is a wonderful child.
Booth. You shouldn't feel inadequate.
Yeah. well. I'm perfectly capable
of raising my own kid.
You're being defensive.
- I am not.
- It's because you only have one child.
When you procreate in multiples.
there's less pressure.
Thank you. I feel much better.
This way. Have a seat.
I apologize. Agent Booth.
When you called and asked
if I knew a Calvin Warren...
I just didn't put it together
with the Kings' "manny. "
- Oh. so you did know him?
- Yes. butjust as Cal.
My son is on the same lacrosse team
as the King boy.
- Did you have any more dealings with him?
- I'm afraid not.
Actually. no.
That's not true. I'm sorry again.
Calvin came along with us one time...
when I took the King children
up for a ride.
- A ride?
- I'm a pilot.
I own a Seneca Five.
Cal got sick. and. well. the boys
thought that was hilarious.
You wouldn't happen to know how Cal Warren
got a prescription for painkillers from you?
Oh. Isn't that obvious?
That's why he brought
Royce King to me to be stitched up-
to steal my prescription pad.
Right. I have no further questions.
So. you know. thanks for coming in.
I just feel stupid for not being able
to put the face with the name.
- I'm so sorry for wasting your time.
- No worries. Have a nice day.
Hey. So you know
that thing where you insist...
that all information goes through you?
Yes. and I'm afraid
I'm immovable on the subject.
And you send out little e-mails
summarizing the case so far?
Yes. Plus. I check those e-mails to see
if they've been opened.
That's a very good system.
- Thank you.
- Because if you weren't checking...
I probably never
would've read the e-mail...
that said Booth questioned
a flying dermatologist.
I hope you're not trying
to get some free lotion.
I ran the accelerant samples
through the G.C. mass spec.
- There were traces of tetraethyl lead.
- Have we changed the subject?
No. Because if you hadn't been so anal
about the e-mails...
I never would've known
that I discovered something...
- that wasn't merely interesting. but vital to the investigation.
- Which is tetraethyl lead?
Tetraethyl lead was a common
anti-knock additive in gasoline...
that went out with catalytic
converters and unleaded gas.
- Does the flying dermatologist drive a vintage car?
- Maybe.
But for sure. the flying
dermatologist flies a plane.
Aviation gas?
The victim's remains were
incinerated by aviation gas.
I'll let Booth know.
Hopefully she hasn't flown the coop
while you were getting to the point.
I was just trying to be nice.
- You lied to me.
- Yes.
I wrote Cal a prescription
for painkillers.
I shouldn't have.
- That's the truth.
- Well. not this time. Doc.
Now that I know that
you're a world-class liar...
I came just a little bit more
prepared this time.
Take a look at those there.
- My flight logs.
- Mm-hmm.
- For the past year.
- Yeah. Hmm.
Oh. lookee there. This one here.
Right here.
Yes. I took Cal flying a few times.
Mm-hmm. Without the kids?
This one here is my favorite-
this particular flight to New York.
You were gone the whole weekend.
All right.
All right. I'll tell you
what you want to know.
No. My husband didn't know I was
having an affair with the Kings' manny.
Would I have killed Cal
to prevent him from finding out?
No. I would not.
Why? Because my husband
doesn't give a damn who I boff.
Do I know anyone else
who might wish Cal ill?
Yes. Richard King.
Don't stop. This-
This is great. Keep going.
Cal told me to sell a stock.
He said he had some insider knowledge
that this company was in trouble.
I took the tip. made a killing.
That's when I flew him
to New York to say thank you.
And he said. "You're welcome"-
all weekend.
What does this have to do with Richard King?
It was Richard King's company.
- How's that look. Max?
- Good. It looks good.
I never thought I'd be doing
another experiment.
Dad. what are you doing in here?
Max had a great idea for an experiment.
Dad. you said you wouldn't touch evidence.
Uh. he's been very careful
not to touch the evidence. Dr. Brennan.
You know. your old man-
he reminded me why I got into science.
- To catch murderers?
- No. To figure stuff out in amusing ways.
The bones were incinerated
by aviation fuel.
They just need to know
how strong the wind was. Basic.
So figure out how big a wind
blew the bones.
- Check the weather charts.
- Basic. That's very basic.
But this is the same wind tunnel
you helped me build for the science fair.
Yeah. A basic wind tunnel. honey.
You won first prize.
I made casts that weigh the same
as the bones we found in that tree.
- Now we put
the skull cast into the wind tunnel...
since that was the
largest artifact on the tree.
I didn't touch anything.
The bone begins to move
at wind speeds of 42 miles per hour.
Not enough net force to achieve aerodynamic lift.
But crank it to 69-
I checked the National Weather Service.
There were windstorms
in that area last week.
A strong nor'easter
hit 71 miles per hour late last Tuesday.
That gives us a 48-hour window
for Calvin Warren's murder.
But we still don't know where he was killed
or where the body was dumped.
- Wait a minute. I can figure that out.
- Dad. you're fired.
- What?
- The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.
- NOAA tracks surface conditions.
- Yeah.
So we can calculate where
the bones started out...
if we can plot approximate mass...
and reverse the path
of that nor'easter wind.
The heavier remains will still be near
the original dump site.
- You see? I'm helping.
- Oh. most definitely is helping.
I'm sorry. Dad. but you're fired.
You took part in a forensic experiment.
You said you wouldn't. but you did!
- So now you're fired.
- Dr. Brennan. he didn't touch any of the evidence.
It's okay. kid.
Never mind.
Nice assist. Nick.
Now cage him out. quick.
He's open. Pass it! Pass it!
Hi. Alexa. How are you?
Shouldn't you be. like. studying algebra
or Chinese or solving the world's problems?
I'm cheering for Royce. He's the goalie.
Go! Go!
I watch football.
It's a better sport. It's American.
Lacrosse was invented
by the American Indian.
You can't get much more American than that.
- Hi.
- Oh. God. What now?
Well. I'm just thinking about this whole
insider trading thing.
- I told you everything.
- I'm thinking. Cal. you know. gives you a tip on a stock.
You sell it. You make two. three million dollars.
and it raises questions in my mind.
How did Richard King find out
that Cal spilled insider knowledge?
- That's right. Bones.
- I don't know.
Well. where were you
between last Sunday and Tuesday night?
- Who is she?
- Don't get jealous. Doc. Just answer the question.
I was in San Antonio doing skin grafts
on a firefighter with third-degree burns.
- You've got your own plane.
- You had time to fly back.
You really want me to believe
that Richard King killed Cal?
Cal Warren's remains
were incinerated with aviation gas.
- I didn't kill Cal.
- You know what? She lies a lot.
- I don't think she can help it at all.
- This is my lawyer's card.
- Hmm.
- She's decided not to cooperate.
No. I've decided to watch
my son play lacrosse.
Okay. Here's the surface weather
for Tuesday night...
when that nor'easter blew
the bones into that tree.
Now that red "X"- that's the tree.
- Mm-hmm.
- The bones must've traveled...
along this vector.
Now given the duration of the gusts
and the terrain obstacles...
liftoff must've happened
somewhere between here...
and here.
That's on the edge of
Queen Anne's and Kent County.
- Good job. Excellent experiment.
- Don't thank me.
Thank Max Brennan.
How's it going there. Max?
It's the last day
with my kids this afternoon.
- I'm toast.
- Cam fired you?
No. no. Tempe fired me.
And don't tell me
she hasn't got the authority...
because believe me. I feel fired.
Oh. Sorry. Max.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Sure.
You-Are you. uh-
Are you sleeping with my daughter?
- No.
- Why? Are you gay?
No.
- Is she not attractive enough?
- Bones is beautiful.
Is it because of me? Because I killed one man?
And we both know he deserved it.
All right. just cut it out. Max.
All right. I'll talk to her.
Probably not gonna get anywhere with her.
but I'll talk to her.
You're a good man.
And I want that for her.
And now I gotta go
blow up some soda for some kids.
Okay. according to the calculations...
the bones must've started out
from somewhere in this vicinity.
- You know something. Bones?
It's tough being a father.
Parker will be fine.
Peer groups and random
environmental factors...
are far more important than family.
- How is that a good thing?
- Over here.
Agent Booth. over here.
- This must've been where the body was burned.
- You think?
Femur. pelvis. sternum.
Gunshot trauma to the sternal angle.
The buckshot embedded
in the anterior surface indicates...
that the murder weapon
was a 12-gauge shotgun.
- But I thought Cal was strangled.
- He was-
- Strangled. shot and set on fire.
- Whoa.
Someone wanted to make sure
he didn't get home.
Hey. Bones. Look at that family crest.
Looks like that someone came
from the Kings' country home.
Mr. King. we'd like to ask you
a few questions about your nanny.
I really don't see
how I can help you. Agent Booth.
- My wife deals with the staff.
- Do you own a 12-gauge shotgun?
Yeah. Several.
You're welcome to examine them.
Two months ago. Cal gave an investor
insider knowledge about your company.
- I didn't know that.
- And if you had known?
- I suppose I would have tried to fire him.
- Tried?
- Well. I don't think that Elsbeth would have allowed it.
- Why?
- Was she having an affair with him?
- Oh. Bones- Good one.
- You two need to learn focus.
- Excuse me?
- Focus.
Either accuse me of killing Cal...
because he betrayed business secrets
or because he had sex with my wife.
And then once you've chosen.
then contact my lawyers.
I'd go with the business motive.
I'm very happily married.
Okay. that guy's one cool customer.
- Ooh. Cool. like a- like a murderer?
- No. I don't know. okay?
I just don't see him losing his temper...
or taking on some Special Forces vet.
That's all.
All right. do you think that dog
comes with a saddle. huh?
Follow me. Bones. will ya. for a second?
What's going on? What are you doing?
Ahh.
Are you gonna urinate in the gas
tank as an act of vandalism?
Are you kidding me. Bones?
I would never do something like that
to this fine Italian automobile.
Beautiful car. It's Italian. Bones.
Just remember that.
Italians make the best automobiles.
Yeah. there it is.
Okay. Bones. Give me. uh.
one of your little Baggies.
- I didn't bring evidence bags.
- Thanks. Bones. Appreciate it.
- You come prepared.
- We're not at a crime scene.
- Why would I bring evidence bags?
- You always have evidence bags.
I've. um- I've decided I'm gonna
leave theJeffersonian.
- Why?
- Uh. because I fired him.
- You can do that?
- Oh. yeah. Believe me. she can do it.
Well. it's all about proximity
to forensic evidence.
Uh. don't take any offense.
but that's a lot of crap.
It's about a proximity to me. Right?
Well. in my opinion...
it isn't your father's presence
that's causing you anxiety.
It's the memory of his absence.
I can understand quantum mechanics.
but I can't understand you.
Well. make it easy.
I'm leaving theJeffersonian.
You are?
- But I'm staying with you.
- What? Oh- In my house?
No. No. no.
- Wait. is that an offer?
- No. Would you-Would you want me to offer?
No. no. But thanks for the offer.
No. It wasn't an offer.
It was just a question.
He isn't saying
he's literally staying with you.
He's promising never to abandon you again.
I'm sorry. but if it wasn't for
that evidence thing. I'd-
- I'd let you keep your job.
- That's simply not true.
Hey. it's all right.
We're good.
Uhh! Nothing I say has any impact.
Uh. I should get back to work.
Geez.
Did she leave any money?
- About the fractured hyoid.
- Yes?
I was just remembering about a tapeworm.
I'm gonna need more than that.
There was a tapeworm in the line.
the one that went to the beer keg.
I was working as a barback a couple years ago.
There's no flow from the tap line.
- First assumption- Kink in the line. right?
- What else could it be?
There was a tapeworm in
the line. eight inches long.
- I learned something from that.
- Drink bottled beer?
The tap don't flow.
you assume the line's got a kink.
A guy's hyoid is broken...
you assume he died from getting strangled.
You found a tapeworm?
I mean metaphorically.
Yeah. but I don't know if it's a tapeworm.
I need Dr. Brennan.
Dr. Saroyan?
I am so your most valuable player.
Now this is the profile
of the accelerant we found on the bones.
- Aviation gas.
- And this is the profile of the gas we took off Booth's tie.
Richard King's car runs on "av" gas?
He could've siphoned it out of his own car
to burn Cal Warren's remains.
- And what is this anomaly?
- C6H807.
- Citric acid?
- It's my considered belief...
that Agent Booth spilled orange juice on his tie.
I look forward to seeing him
explain that to a jury.
Booth. it's Cam.
I think you're gonna want to get yourself
a warrant to arrest Richard King.
Fractures on the transverse
processes of the C2-
both sides and the spinous process.
And check out the occipital protuberance.
- Oh. yes.
- Maybe this will help Booth keep Richard King in detention.
Cal wasn't strangled postmortem.
He was dragged.
Strangulation is the kink.
Dragging is the tapeworm.
The pattern of marks is evenly spaced...
- as if it were from a series of connected prongs.
- What would do that?
- A choke chain.
- Richard King's a big strong guy.
I don't see him dragging
a dead body around on a choke chain.
That's because he didn't.
The angle of the fracture is 18 degrees.
Assuming a standard four-foot leash...
whoever dragged
the victim is at most 5'5".
Elsbeth King.
So. you sure you don't want your attorney
present. Mrs. King?
- Let's just get this over with.
- Okay. Sounds good to me.
Here's. uh. what I'm thinking.
I'm thinking that your country home
is less than a mile...
from the spot where Cal's body was burned.
You had access to the shotgun.
the aviation gas.
You know how many people
work for us. Agent Booth?
Every single one of them had access.
Yeah. but I don't think any of them really
would have cared if they found out...
that Cal Warren was trying to destroy
your husband's company.
Hmm.
You have a nice life.
I'm sure you got really angry when
you found out that it was all going away.
Hmm.
Hmm?
You don't understand.
It wasn't about the money.
I had to protect my family.
- What do you think?
- In my professional opinion. she didn't whack him.
What? Come on. Cal betrayed them.
Come on. Sweets. For once. you were right.
- Embrace the wind. my friend.
- I'm sorry.
But it's Kinesics 101. You know.
you pushed all the right buttons.
But instead of her ego defense system
triggering a stress response state...
- she went straight to a tacit confession.
- Right.
Which means she did it.
No. It means she didn't do it...
but she wants you to believe that she did.
- Why would she want to do that?
- 'Cause she's covering for someone.
The only honest thing that she said
was that she had to protect her family.
- So we're back to square one.
- Sort of.
Geez.
Sweets. let me ask you something. Uh-
I mean. you're a smart guy.
You went to private school. right?
Yeah. With perfect attendance
through sixth grade. might I add.
Yeah. that's great. Um-
You don't think that I'm a lousy dad...
for not sending my son
to private school. huh?
No. But you'd be a lousy father
if you didn't torture yourself about it.
Thanks.
Oh. hold on. Booth.
I reviewed the placement
of the shotgun pellet wounds.
The trajectory indicates
that whoever shot Cal...
was significantly shorter than Mrs. King.
I don't think she did it.
Right. Thanks.
You see. we got a court order
for your cell phone and your laptop.
You know. nothing you text or I.M.
is really private.
- I knew that.
- Really?
Because. you know.
we checked your text messages...
and we found one from a couple weeks ago
that's a little weird.
This one is from
the night that Cal was killed.
"Bring it over now. Parents both gone. '"
- Stop this. Richard.
- No. I want to hear it.
It turns out that Alexa here
had a project due on Ancient Greece.
Mmm. You spent three days
complaining about it.
- Why didn't you just do it?
- I didn't want to. It was stupid.
Stupid? Oh.
How about this one?
"'De' manny will do it.
He can't say no. He works for me. "
But Cal really did say no. didn't he?
Because you paid a hundred bucks to
somebody else to do it for you.
Someone by the name of Dakota Shearcroft?
- Oh. my God.
- Yeah. I think it's a stupid name too.
So what happened? Did Cal catch you?
He threatened to tell the school.
- Why wouldn't he have told us?
- Cal said you wouldn't do anything. You never do.
- He said I had to learn a lesson.
- What kind of lesson?
They would've kicked me out of school.
Zero tolerance.
My friends are at that school.
I got the gun out of the garage.
and I shot him.
Mom came home and saw.
I drove the body to the country house...
took it into the woods and burned it.
She's my daughter. I had to protect her.
No. You did what you always do-
make everything bad go away.
It's counterproductive to raise children
in a world without consequences.
Well. it looks like little Alexa here
is gonna have to come face to face...
with some pretty nasty consequences.
But not the kind of consequences
you're gonna have to face. Mrs. King.
Okay. Parker. this is called
the candy mint soda experiment.
You can do this for your dad at home.
So Mom copped to conspiracy
to avoid trial.
She'll spend some time in prison.
- How much?
- Not enough.
In my opinion. she ruined
that little girl's life.
What about the little girl?
Removed from the family.
Institutionalized for a couple years.
Then it's back to ponies and tennis lessons?
- Mm-hmm.
- Well. Caroline should charge her as an adult.
She's 11 years old. Bones.
Yeah. well. she's old enough
to speak Chinese.
Uh. they don't take that into account.
I tell ya. man. when
that little girl killed Cal Warren...
she killed the best father she had.
- Well. sometimes it's hard to appreciate what you've got.
- Mmm.
- You put the mints in the tube.
- Okay.
Look at him. Parker's
never liked science before.
So are you still thinking
of sending him to Woodbury?
I torched the application.
I'm thinking there's something
to be said for middle class.
That's right. Put them all in there.
- You sure he's gonna be all right?
- Sure.
- You're doing a great job. Parker.
- Well. probably.
Probably?
Like. what do you mean "probably"?
I mean. what the hell they doing anyways?
Disrupting the surface tension
of a two-liter cola.
Right.
Is that the last one?
All right. Put it in the tube.
And then we'll both take a step back.
Don't fire Max. Let him keep his job.
You know. he's a teacher.
He's not a janitor.
I can't overlook the sanctity
of the forensic lab. Booth.
Yeah. Maybe you can overlook it for me?
- For you?
- Yeah.
- Personal favor.
- What. like a partner thing?
Partner thing.
I know you. Booth.
You're trying to do me a favor
by telling me it's a favor for you.
No. Mm-mmm. No. I-
I can't afford that school.
I can't enrich Parker.
Not with the science thing. but you can.
Max can.
Whoa!
That was so cool! Can we do it again?
Daddy. Daddy! Look what I did!
I blew it up!
Yeah. I saw. little man.
That's not magic. That's-
- Max K.. the science way!
- Look at my dad.
Look at my little boy there with your dad.
Okay.
Yes.
- All right.
- Thanks. Bones.
# Change the way I feel #
Thanks.
# And the sun will rise #
# The sun will save
from the night #
# The sun will change #
# Change the way I feel ##
What's that mean?
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today